A Guide to the J. Carlton Bowles papers, 1942-1947
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
J. Carlton Bowles papers, 1942-1947
The Library of Virginia
53504
.175 cubic feet (1 box)
J. Carlton Bowles
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Mary Lynn B. Fothergill, Roanoke, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Joyce Carlton Bowles was born 15 April 1922 in Franklin County, Virginia, to John Thomas Bowles (1865-1953) and Ora B. Hubbard Bowles (1886-1968). He attended public schools, then worked as a cabinet maker's assistant. During World War II, Bowles served in the 313th Infantry, 79th Division, United States Army, and received a Bronze Star and a Purple Heart. After World War II, he worked for the E. I. DuPont plant in Martinsville, Virginia. Bowles married Virginia Louise Hodges 26 June 1947, and they had two children. Bowles died in Rocky Mount, Virginia, 19 May 2006, and is buried in Mountain View Memorial Park in Rocky Mount.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1942-1945, of J. Carlton Bowles of Franklin County, Virginia, detailing his service in World War II, including baptism certificate; orders regarding battle honors and awards; postcards of Paris, France; selective service notifications; separation reports and honorable discharge papers; and Veterans Administration papers. Papers also include the SS Asa Gray Hound newsletter, December 1945, and histories of the 79th Division, United States Army.
Contents List
- Photographs (Folder 1)
- Selective Service postcards, 1942 (Folder 2)
- Letters and papers, 1944-1945 (Folder 3)
- Postcards, 1945 (Folder 4)
- Honors and awards, 1945 (Folder 5)
- Separation report and honorable discharge papers, October 1945 (Folder 6)
- Veterans Administration papers, 1946-1947 (Folder 7)
- SS Asa Gray Hound newsletter, December 1945 (Folder 8)
- Combat History of the 79th Inf. Div.: East of the Rhine, April 20, 1945, 1945 (Folder 10)
- Story of the 79t: The Cross of Lorraine Division, 1945 (Folder 10)